Guide to the Cornell University Department of Theatre Arts records, 1893-2008.
Cornell University Department of Theatre Arts records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Department of Theatre Arts records, 1893-2008.
14-24-2114
Cornell University. Dept. of Theatre Arts.
49.1 cubic feet
Correspondence, financial records, photographs, printed materials, scrapbooks.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Department of Theatre Arts (fomerly the Department of Public Speaking and then the Department of Speech and Drama) as well as the Cornell Dramatic Club and the Cornell University Theatre.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Department of Theatre Arts originated from the Department of Elocution and Oratory which formed around 1898. In 1914 the department changed its name to become the Department of Public Speaking, and in 1942 it became the Department of Speech and Drama. The department name changed again in 1967 to become the Department of Theatre Arts. Since 1996 the name has been the Department of Theatre, Film and Dance. The first drama courses offered for credit were held in the summer of 1922 and the 1923-1924 academic year and they were taught by Alexander M. Drummond (also referred to as A.M. Drummond).
The Cornell Dramatic Club (CDC) formed in March 1909 and its first production, staged at the Lyceum Theater, was "An Enemy of the People" by Henrik Ibsen, directed by Professor Smiley Blanton. Professor Blanton served as the CDC's director until 1911 when Lew D. Fallis assumed the responsibility for a year. Alexander M. Drummond became the director in 1912 and served until 1947. Walter H. Stainton served from 1947 to 1952 and George McCalmon served from 1952 until his death in 1965. Cornell University Theatre (CU Theatre) was created in 1930 by the Trustees of the University to bring together the theatre-related activities at Cornell. CU Theatre was supervised by the Department of Public Speaking, and Professor Drummond served as its director until 1952 when he retired from the University. George McCalmon took over as director after Drummond's retirement.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection is comprised of records from the Department of Theatre Arts, its predecessor departments (Public Speaking; Speech and Drama) and their activities as well as the records of the Cornell Dramatic Club and Cornell University Theatre. The collection is organized into four series: Public Speaking and Debate Contests; Speech and Drama Courses; Department Administration Files; and Cornell University Theatre and Cornell Dramatic Club. The bulk of the collection material relates to the CDC and CU Theatre. Also includes publications relating to "An American Festival: A Celebration of Heritage, Community, and the Arts to Mark the Opening of the Cornell University Center for Theatre Arts, September 17-27, 1989" include programs, "Final Report & Evaluation," by John W. Suter. Also From the Ground Up: Grassroots Theater in Historical and Contemporary Perspective, edited by Dudley Cocke, Harry Newman, and Janet Salmons-Rue, Community Based Arts Project, Cornell University, 1993.
The first series, Public Speaking and Debate Contests, contains speeches from the Woodford Prize contest in public speaking, programs for the Class of 1886 Memorial Prize, the Class of 1894 Memorial Prize in Debate, and the Woodford Prize, and correspondence files relating to the contests. The collections of speeches and programs are not complete. Additional Woodford Prize materials can be found in the Prize Essay collection, #7-9-1317
The materials in the second series, Speech and Drama Courses, largely date from the 1950s and 1960s and include syllabi, exams, instructors' guides, and assignment sheets.
The third series, Department Administration Files, dates largely from the 1970s and 1980s but also includes materials from the 1950s and 1960s. It includes select faculty meeting and executive committee minutes, annual reports, fellowship and endowment correspondence, and other correspondence files on a variety of administrative issues. The series contains a few administrative files on the speech clinic that was associated with the Department of Speech and Drama.
The fourth series, Cornell University Theatre and Cornell Dramatic Club, comprises the largest group of materials in the collection. It contains business and financial records of the CDC, CU Theatre and Summer Theatre, box office reports, correspondence, membership lists, and a variety of other subject files on Cornell theater activities. The series contains eight subseries: Alexander Drummond; Walter H. Stainton; George McCalmon; Publicity and Correspondence; Scripts and Prompt Books; Scrapbooks and Memorabilia; Programs, Posters and other Printed Materials; and Photographs and Slides. The subseries of materials for Drummond, Stainton and McCalmon contain files from their involvement as directors of the CDC and/or CU Theatre. Alexander Drummond and Walter Stainton also have separate collections of their papers in the University Archives (RMC collection numbers 14-24-435 and 14-24-573 respectively). The subseries Publicity and Correspondence dates form the 1950s and 1960s and contains materials relating to the promotion of individual plays. The subseries Programs, Posters, and other Printed Materials contains programs, playbills, posters, broadsides, and other printed materials. The CDC and CU Theatre programs are organized chronologically by season. Programs for productions performed by outside groups but sponsored by the CDC or CU Theatre are listed separately. The collection does not contain a complete run of programs from Cornell theater productions. Additionally the programs listed in the guide represent only those programs housed in the collection and not a complete list of theater productions at Cornell. Lists of CDC productions from 1908 to 1960 can be found in the general files of the CU Theatre and CDC series. The Programs subseries also contains programs from other Cornell theater groups such as Kermis and the Cornell Women's Dramatic Club (which merged with the CDC in 1925).
Also, a Cornell Women's Dramatic Club scrapbook and "Report of the Committee on Amalgamation", May 25, 1925.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Dept. of Theatre Arts.; Drummond, A. M. (Alexander Magnus), 1884-1956.; McCalmon, George, d. 1965.; Stainton, Walter.; Cornell Dramatic Club.; Cornell Women's Dramatic Club.; Cornell University. Dept. of Public Speaking.; Cornell University. Dept. of Speech and Drama.; Cornell University. Summer Theatre.; Cornell University Theatre.; New York State Plays Project.
Subjects:
Drama--Study and teaching.; One-act plays.; Oratory--Competitions.; Speech--Study and teaching.; Theater--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides.; Financial records.; Photographs.; Prompt books.; Scrapbooks.; Scripts (documents).; Theater programs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Public Speaking and Debate Contests
Series II. Speech and Drama Courses
Series III. Department Administration Files
Subseries: Files of Gerald Canter, Director of the Speech Clinic, Dept. of Speech and Drama
Series IV. Cornell University Theatre and Cornell Dramatic Club
Subseries: Alexander Drummond
Subseries: Walter H. Stainton
Subseries: George McCalmon
Subseries: Publicity and Correspondence
Subseries: Scripts and Prompt Books
Subseries: One-act plays for A. M. Drummond course
Subseries: Scrapbooks and Memorabilia
Subseries: Programs, Posters and other Printed Materials
Subseries: Regular and Summer Season Programs
Subseries: Sponsored Performances
Subseries: Photographs and Slides
RELATED MATERIALS
Alexander M. Drummond papers, 1917-1956. #14-24-435.
Walter Stainton papers. #14-24-573.
Florence Evelyn Dahme papers. #37-6-m.554.
American Agriculturist Play Dept. Scripts, 1941-1954. #4924
Extempore speaking: a series of exercises based on studies in American History and Institutions; by Duncan Campbell Lee, A.M., Assistant Professor of Elocution and Oratory in Cornell University; 1897.
NOTES
Combines the contents of former collections #14-24-1266, 14-24-1641, 14-24-708, 14-24-750, 14-24-1438, 14-24-1584, 14-24-1049 and 37-6-640.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Public Speaking and Debate Contests
  - Woodford Prize Contest speeches (Box 15, Folder 1-43)
    Includes 1919-1928, 1930-1943, 1947-1963, 1967, undated
  - Public speaking contest broadsides (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Columbia-Cornell Debate, Cornell Alumni News, May 1, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Debating contest programs, correspondence, 1923, 1935, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Debating contest broadsides (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Prize information, circa 1959-1964 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - 1886 Memorial Prize programs, 1905, 1920-1942 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - 1894 Memorial Prize Debate programs, 1901, 1917-1941 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Woodford Prize Contest programs, 1915-1943 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Fuertes Memorial Contest program, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Speeches, declamations and reports for Woodford and Memorial Prizes, etc., early 1900s (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Photographs of various Memorial Prize, Woodford Prize and Debate participants, 1890s-1920s (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Woodford Prize information and correspondence, 1950s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Class of 1894 Memorial Prize in Debate (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - 1886 Memorial Prize announcements, correspondence, 1950s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - 1886 Memorial Prize winners (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Certificates for Class of 1886 Memorial Prize and Class of 1896 Memorial Prize in Debate, 1901-1902 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Announcements for Dept. of Speech and Drama lectures, 1960s (Box 49, Folder 4)
- Series II. Speech and Drama Courses
  - Materials relative to courses in argumentation, #213 and 301, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Speech and Drama 202 (Persuasion) - course materials, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Speech and Drama 402, "Psychology of Persuasion" (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Speech and Drama 102,202 course material (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Course materials for Speech and Drama 103 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Course materials for Speech and Drama 105, circa 1957-1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Notes to instructors, Speech and Drama 101,201, 1950s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Instructors' schedules, Speech and Drama 101,201, 1950s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Speech 201, 101 exams (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Student schedules; "assignments and materials" packets for public speaking class 101,201, 1949-1967 (Box 16, Folder 9-17)
  - Speech and Drama 205 course materials, circa 1957-1965 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Speech 101, 201 course questionnaires (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Bibliographer of Rhetorical Theory by Frederick W. Haberman, Used by graduate students in rhetoric-public address, 1957-1967 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - The Rhetoricians, 1960s; Speech and Drama Dept. interest group made up of graduate students, faculty, and undergraduate majors in rhetoric and public address (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Speech behavior Ph.D. announcement (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Series III. Department Administration Files
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - MFA Governance Board, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ad-Hoc Committees, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - British American Drama Academy, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cinema Film Showing Policies, 1968-1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - A. M. Drummond Fellowship, 1957-1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Charles B. Moss Scholarship Endowment, 1960-1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Post-Modern Culture/Literature Conference, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Heermans Prize miscellaneous (alias names, list of winners), 1935-1946 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Forbes Heermans and McCalmon Playwriting Contests, 1937, 1967-1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Forbes Heermans Endowment, 1957-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Heermans McCalmon committee, publicity (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Heermans McCalmon playwriting winners, 1961-1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Forbes Heermans/McCalmon Playwriting Contest, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Graduate Education Review Committee, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Graduate School correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - University Resident Theatre Association, 1971-1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - New performing arts building (Schwartz Center), 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Department assessment, mission statement, division reports, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Production support, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Faculty recruitment, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - URTA auditions (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Lincoln Hall theatre reading room, 1967-1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Cornell endowments correspondence, 1957-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Budget, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Teaching assistants, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Council on International Education Exchange - Film with Paris, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Summer Theatre, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Course catalog notes, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Course catalog and scheduling notes, 1971-1982 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Course catalog, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Course catalog notes, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Courses (Box 3, Folder 36-39)
    Includes Spring-Fall 1982 and Summer 1983
  - Department and CDC correspondence, Carroll C. Arnold, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Annual reports, 1936-1951 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Executive Development Program, Public Speaking - Wilson, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Subseries: Files of Gerald Canter, Director of the Speech Clinic, Dept. of Speech and Drama, circa 1962
    - Curriculum (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Office of Vocational Rehabilitation (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Masters degrees (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Education screening (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Department business (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Speech and Drama certification, 1957-1963 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Speech and Drama course changes, 1954-1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - School of Education speech testing, 1957-1961 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Binghamton Public Schools speech survey, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Speech Clinic annual reports, 1951-1963 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1981-1983 (Box 19, Folder 5-7)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1982-1983, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
  - Department Chair correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Summer session, 1970-1983 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Lecturer hiring procedures, 1980-1984 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Annual reports, 1981-1984 (Box 19, Folder 13-15)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Undergraduate program amendments, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Playwriting awards, 1970-1984 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Summer repertory funding, 1972-1978 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Theatre annual financial reports, 1970-1978 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Chairmanship of Theatre Department, 1968-1982 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Departmental self-study, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Art and Sciences budget survey, 1977-1979 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Academic planning review, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Annual report materials (Box 19, Folder 26-31)
    Includes 1974/1975, 1977/1978-1983/1984
  - Teaching assistants, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Faculty assignments, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Course catalog, 1982-1986 (Box 19, Folder 34-37)
  - Student papers (The Stage is Set by Lee Simonson; The Art Theater by Sheldon Cheney; The Unit Set by John Herod; Modern Theories of Dramatic Production by John Colby Lewis III, undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Theatre Arts program booklet (Box 19, Folder 39)
- Series IV. Cornell University Theatre and Cornell Dramatic Club
  - CDC Secretary-Treasurer's account book, 1933-1948; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - CDC minute book, 1909-1929; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - CDC and CU Theatre business records book, 1939-1946; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - CDC box office reports, 1934-1938; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - CDC box office reports, 1940-1946; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - CDC box office reports, 1947-1949; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - Theatre financial ledger book, 1928-1931; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - Theatre financial ledger book, 1935-1939; Bound volume (Box 25)
  - CDC account book, 1919-1936; Bound volume (Box 52)
  - CDC account book, 1943-1944; Bound volume (Box 52)
  - CDC account book, 1947-1948; Bound volume (Box 52)
  - CDC Summer Theatre account book, 1941-1948; Bound volume (Box 52)
  - CDC financial report, 1944-1950 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
  - CDC business/finances (Box 22, Folder 8-10)
    Includes 1914-1917, 1921-1923, 1925-1929
  - CDC business, 1927-1935 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - CDC accounts/finances, 1929-1945 (Box 22, Folder 12-13)
  - CDC financial statements, 1932-1940 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Financial reports-plays, 1931-1946 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Theatre financial and business reports, 1940-1945 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - CDC financial reports, 1945-1948 (Box 22, Folder 17-18)
  - CDC workshop finances, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - CDC ledgers, 1960s; 2 bound volumes (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Theatre house manager reports, 1941-1944 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous theater/equipment magazines, catalogs, publications, 1936-1951; (includes autographed photo of Thomas Wilfred) (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Summer Theatre ledger book, 1934; Bound volume (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Summer Theatre financial reports, 1947, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 24-26)
  - Summer Theatre business and financial, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Summer Theatre financial papers, 1927-1935 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Summer Theatre accounts, 1935-1939; Bound volumes (Box 22, Folder 29-33)
  - Play ledger book, 1939-1943; Bound volume (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Summer Theatre financial report, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Summer Theatre financial/staff, 1940-1946 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Summer Theatre reports, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Box office reports (Box 22, Folder 38-42)
    Includes 1930-1933, 1936-1940, 1950-1955
  - Kita Noh Theatre Co., Cornell performance, October 2, 1989; V-817; VHS videotape (Box 23)
  - CDC annual dance card, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, Pillars of Society and An Enemy of the People, circa 1909 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Logo designs for Ithaca Repertory Theatre, Summer 1976 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings; program for "Inspector General", circa 1909; 1911 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Playwright's Notebook of New York State, circa 1949 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Studio reports and production schedules, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Drummond Studio information, circa 1962 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Japanese Noh drama, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Shakespeare Celebration, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - The Knack tour, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Festival of Contemporary Arts, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Cornell University Theatre exhibit caption (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Caption cards for Library's display on CDC's 50th anniversary, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper clippings, circa 1954 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clippings, Ithaca Journal, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Latin America tour - George McCalmon correspondence and newspaper clippings, circa 1962 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - CDC constitutions/by-laws (Box 23, Folder 17)
    Includes 1925-1929, 1948, 1959, 1969
  - CDC Manual of Play Production, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Procedure for the general tryout (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - List of plays performed by the Cornell Dramatic Club, 1908-1960 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - CDC Council minutes, 1952-1956 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Studio '57 instructions for directors of one acts, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - CDC Open House, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - CDC 50th anniversary-correspondence and planning materials (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - CDC member lists (includes Cornell Women's Dramatic Club), 1910-1947 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - CDC members lists, 1909-1938, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - CDC officers and members lists, 1926-1944 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - First President's Prize correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Pyramus and Thisbe-correspondence, production notes, scripts, 1952-1961 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Drummond bequest and "Uncle Vanya" production, 1957-1960 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Alexander Drummond (Box 23, Folder 31)
    [contains photograph]
  - A.M. Drummond Playwriting Contest announcements and judges' forms, circa 1962-1971 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - CDC and CU Theatre annual letter to former members, 1916-1965 (incomplete) (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Alumni news clippings (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - 50th anniversary radio program script, 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - CDC meeting minutes, 1929-1942 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - The Book of Job, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Jacob Gould Schurman to CDC, 1909 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - News and press releases, circa 1916-1917 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Willard Straight Theatre opening, The Contrast correspondence, 1925 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Articles from Cornell publications and newspaper clippings, 1916-1934 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - List of CDC productions, 1919-1946 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Women's Dramatic Club "Alice in Wonderland", 1927-1928 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Inventory - costumes, financial, undated (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - List of Westminster props and scenery, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Alfred University performance of A Day in the Vineyard, 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Blueprint of the seating plan of the Goldwin Smith amphitheatre, The amphitheatre was used for dramatic productions before Willard Straight Hall was built. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Alexander Drummond
    - Articles on scene design, 1946-1948 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - The Country Theatre, State Fair, 1920-1955 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - National Association of Teachers of Speech correspondence, Drummond, 1921-1922 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - National Association of Teachers of Speech correspondence, Drummond, Country Theater, 1919-1923 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Country/Rural Theater correspondence, clippings, 1918-1920 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Drummond correspondence, 1919-1921 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - The Little Country Theatre correspondence, clippings, etc., 1920-1926 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Play Production in the Country Theatre extension bulletin by Drummond manuscript, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - All's Well That Ends Well (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - National Theatre Company Army theatre program correspondence and reports, 1940-1944 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Festival of Contemporary Arts, 1945-1946 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Chekhov Theatre Studio correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Willard Straight Theatre management, 1923-1947 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Willard Straight building administration, 1925-1946 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Willard Straight Theatre design, 1922-1925 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Film and miscellaneous expenses, 1941-1946 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, reports, financial information, 1927-1947 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Little Country Theatre (State Fair), 1921-1924 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Theatre Lighting Past and Present by the Ward Leonard Electric Company, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Permissions for Drummond book, 1937-1939 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - A. Drummond's theatre notebook, circa 1932 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Sketches of scenery and stage, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - CDC and Drummond correspondence, 1916-1923 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Essays and notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
  - Walter H. Stainton
    - Theatre Service Organization of Buffalo correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous Stainton correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 20, Folder 37-38)